Hello friends let's talk about some
updates with the brain organoids yes the
tiny human brains that we can grow in a
jar first off the reason that I didn't
cover this a group that claimed that
they put a brain organoid in a robot
this was not real there are however
brain organoids that have been popped in
robots you can find that information at
UC San Diego with Allison merer lab and
of course don't get me wrong I've talked
to Allison several times now he seems
like an amazing person but I do get the
idea that he's trying to be a MTH
scientist brain in a jar formerly just
philosophical puzzle is now a reality
one thing people ask me a lot is do the
brain organoids sleep that's a difficult
question to answer they do have complex
wavelengths that seem to rise and fall
but it seems they're already in an
internal sleep they experience Delta
brain waves which are similar to that of
a premature babies or an adults when
they're sleeping but during this stage
they can still learn and process new
information and recall it one of the
larger problems with them is figuring
out what they're thinking and many
scientists are making more refined ways
to communicate with their electrical
signals many scientists are also trying
to answer the question of what will it
look like when they reach Consciousness
and nobody believes they're conscious
yet that is yet most people acknowledge
the symbolic value of taking something
that is from us and creating the most
intimate part of our body our brains
recreating them in a way that can be
used in robotic slavery many scientists
have the perspective that if we focus
specifically on the point at which we
reach Consciousness we're going to
forget a lot of the other cultural
aspects of utilizing our brains in this
manner if we only wait for Consciousness
are we going to be creating suffering in
a creature that we don't understand how
to communicate with